<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the King: a proclamation. James R. Whereas we have by a former proclamation of the eight and twentieth day of February last, for the reasons therein set forth, declared and ordained amongst other things, that corn and meal should be sold to such persons as should be employed by us to make stores and magazins for the use of our army, ...</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1685-1688 : James II)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B25097</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99886421</idno>
  <idno type="VID">186675</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2248536386</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing J301</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide C.21.f.12[100]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide G.6022[110]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R225990</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99886421</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99886421e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B25097)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 186675)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C5:2[100]; C23:1[110])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the King: a proclamation. James R. Whereas we have by a former proclamation of the eight and twentieth day of February last, for the reasons therein set forth, declared and ordained amongst other things, that corn and meal should be sold to such persons as should be employed by us to make stores and magazins for the use of our army, ...</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1685-1688 : James II)</author>
                  <author>James II, King of England, 1633-1701.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([2] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for alderman James Malone printer to the King's most excellent Majesty; and are to sold at his shop in Skinnerrow. And by Andrew Crook on Ormond-Key,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Dublin, :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1689 [i.e. 1690]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Title from caption title and opening lines of text.</note>
                  <note>"Given at our court at Dublin-Castle the 25th day of March 1690."</note>
                  <note>Date of publication given according to Lady Day dating.</note>
                  <note>Arms 186.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="geographic_name">Ireland --  History --  War of 1689-1691 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03 </date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-09 </date>
            <label>Simon Charles </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-09 </date>
            <label>Simon Charles</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:186675:1"/>
            <head type="illustration">
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>royal blazon or coat of arms</figDesc>
                  <q>HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</q>
                  <q>DIEV ET MON DROIT</q>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <opener>
               <signed>BY THE KING:</signed>
            </opener>
            <head>A PROCLAMATION.</head>
            <opener>
               <signed>JAMES R.</signed>
            </opener>
            <p>WHEREAS We have by a former Proclamation of the eight and twentieth day of <hi>February</hi> last, for the Reasons therein set forth, Declared and Ordained amongst other things, that Corn and Meal should be sold to such persons as should be Employed by Vs to make Stores and Magazins for the use of Our Army, at the se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral Rates therein expressed; believing, that by lessening the Price of Corn and Meal to be Bought for Our Stores, the Rate thereof should abate be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween Our Subjects. And whereas We have since received Information, that the Farmers and others, Owners of such Corn and Meal, have rather ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken Occasion from Our said Proclamation, to raise the Price thereof far higher than ever it was before, which may be of very evil consequence, if not speedily prevented: For remedy whereof, We have thought fit, by the Advice of Our Privy Council, to Declare and Ordain, that all Corn and Meal be sold for the future in all Markets, and other Places, to all Our Loving Subjects who shall have occasion to Buy the same, at no higher Price than the Rates following; that is to say, Five and twenty shillings the Barrel of the best Wheat, Three and twenty shillings the Barrel of ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nary Wheat, Eighteen shillings the Barrel of Meslin, Fourteen shillings the Barrel of the best Beare, Thirteen shillings the Barrel of ordinary Beare, Fourtéen shillings the Barrel of good Barley, in the Counties of
<pb facs="tcp:186675:2"/>
               <hi>Dublin,</hi> City of <hi>Dublin, Meath, Westmeath, Wicklow</hi> and <hi>Kildare;</hi> And seven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teen shillings the Barrel of the best wheat, fifteen shillings the Barrel of ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nary wheat, thirteen shillings the Barrel of the best Beare, twelve shillings the Barrel of ordinary Beare, thirteén shillings the Barrel of good Barley, and fourteen shillings the Barrel of good Oatmeal in all other parts of the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom, the said Barrel to be <hi>Bristol</hi> measure.</p>
            <p>And in case the said <hi>Farmers, Husbandmen</hi> and others that have such Corn or Meal to sell, shall Refuse to sell the same to any of Our People at the Rates aforesaid; We do hereby strictly charge and Command Our Respective Lieutenants, Deputy Lieutenants and Sherriffs of Our Counties of this Our Kingdom, that they and every of them do imediatly compel the said <hi>Far<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mers, Husbandmen</hi> and others within their Respective Counties, to Thrash and Prepare their said Corn and Meal, and to sell the same, or such Proporti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on thereof as shall be thought necessary, at the Respective Rates aforesaid; In which case Our said Lieutenants, Deputy Lieutenants and Sherriffs are to take special care that the said <hi>Farmers, Husbandmen</hi> and others having such Corn or Meal be permitted to keep a sufficient Proportion thereof for the sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sistence of them and their Families, with sufficient Quantity of Barley for Tillage.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Given at Our Court at <hi>Dublin-Castle</hi>
                  <date>the 25<hi>th</hi> Day of <hi>March</hi> 1690. And in the Sixth Year of Our Reign.</date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
            <closer>GOD SAVE THE KING.</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>DƲBLIN,</hi> Printed for Alderman <hi>James Malone</hi> Printer to the King's Most Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellent Majesty; and are to sold at his shop in <hi>Skinnerrow.</hi> And by <hi>Andrew Crook</hi> on <hi>Ormond-key</hi> 1689.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>